JOSPHAT MUTERU

Full Stack Developer 0791983040 Nyeri, Kenya

@ josphatmuteru.netlify.app

github.com/josphatmuteru

PROFILE

A highly motivated software developer and student working towards BSc in Computer Technology, at Multimedia University. I have a strong foundation in computer science principles and a passion for solving complex problems. I have experience working with a wide range of programming languages and frameworks, and am comfortable working on both small and large projects.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

Sem Manager

Jan 2023 - Present

Sem Manager is a start up created by me. It is a web application that allows students to organize their course work and keep track of their progress.

- Built the application's API and database.
- · Designed and built the app's UX/UI.
- Integrated the application's front end and the back end.
- Daily maintenance of code, debugging issues and solving client's problems.

Front End Developer

OFNLTECH Nigeria

July 2022 - Sep 2022

Oluadepe Farms Nigeria LTD (OFNL) is an aquaculture supply company with a social mission to help Nigerian farmers build and grow profitable fish farming businesses.

- Developed a custom Logistics tracking interface that enabled customers to monitor their order's shipping status, live location, and expected arrival time, resulting in a 30% reduction in customer inquiries and a 20% increase in order tracking accuracy.
- Collaborated effectively with a team of developers to meet project deadlines on time and within budget, leveraging strong communication and problem-solving skills to foster a culture of teamwork and collaboration.

EDUCATION

BSc in Computer Technology

Multimedia University Of Kenya

Sep 2020 - Apr 2024.

SKILLS

API Develop	ment							
UX/UI Design								
Web Development								
Version Control								
JavaScript	Node.js	Express.js						
MongoDB	Mongoose	Figma	CSS					

Languages

React

Bootstrap

English						_	
Proficient							
Swahili	 	 	 	 			 _
Native							

HTML

Git